NARRATOR: In 1493, Columbus
led a small band of men
and 24 horses ashore on the
Caribbean island of Hispaniola.
The island people, the Arawaks,
had seen white-skinned men
on Columbus’s first voyage,
but they had never before laid
eyes on the towering beasts
that splashed through the surf that day.
As soon as Columbus
arrived in the Americas,
worlds that had been
separated by vast oceans
for millions of years began to merge.
This process would transform life
on both sides of the Atlantic forever.
Sheep, cattle and chickens were
all imported into the Americas,
as were bananas, coffee and wheat.
And the Americas introduced
the world to tomatoes, cocoa,
as well as corn and peanuts-
foods that now literally feed the world.